♪ ♪
Friends, we are gathered here
to pay our final respects
to our good friend Daniel
Bartholomew Kingsley.
Now, our thoughts
and our prayers
go to his loving wife Felicia
and to his son Aaron,
his daughter Ellen
and her husband Jim
and his four beloved
grandchildren,
and to his many, many friends.
I had the good fortune
to be one of them,
and how I look forward
to that glorious day
when we shall be together
again on Jordan's far shore.
But until then,
Daniel Bartholomew...
D.B., as those of us
who were blessed with
his friendship knew him...
Rest in peace, old friend.
May the grace of God
be with you all. Amen.
Amen.
You know, that wasn't the reunion
we hoped it would be, was it?
I know, but that's
the way life is.
Yeah.
Friends part, miss each other.
Talk about getting
back together,
and somehow, it never happens.
And then, one
day, it's too late.
Hey, how about this?
How about all four of us have
dinner at Ray Templin's Bar?
We'll drink a toast to old
D.B. What do you say?
I haven't been there in so long.
Think the reverend will join us?
You ever know
Jimmy to miss a party?
Of course, that's the old days.
Before he got religion.
Well, there are four of us left.
Tell the truth, Ben.
40 years ago, would
you have ever imagined
that any of us would
have come this far?
I don't know, but we got
lucky, I guess. Real lucky.
The way I see it, we
made our own luck.
Ben?
Hi.
Dad asked me to give you this.
That? What is it?
I don't know.
He gave it to me about
a week before he died.
Said it was for your eyes only.
Oh.
You really meant
a lot to him, Ben.
This court is in session.
Mr. Taft, are you ready to
question the prospective jurors?
I am, Your Honor.
Proceed.
Mr. Morgan, what
is your occupation?
I recently retired from
Hoffman Tool and Die.
42 years, don't you know?
When we first started, we
used to put in a 12-hour day.
Now I don't know
what to do with my time.
Mr. Morgan, in the case of...
Dear Ben,
I'm about to tell you
a 35-year-old secret.
Remember how the five of
us used to go hunting every fall
up around Echo Lake?
What I'm going to tell you
happened on the trip you missed,
because some judge
switched a trial date on you.
Remember that?
Say cheese, boys!
Cheese, boys.
Hey, next time, leave
your shotgun at home, D.B.
The only shooting
you're doing these days
is with that damn camera.
Things would have
turned out so differently
if you'd been along
that weekend, Ben.
But it was just me,
Bud, Jimmy and Lucas.
Who's driving? I
am! Are you crazy?
Bud started passing the bourbon,
and nobody much cared that
we hadn't shot a thing that day.
But we didn't exactly go back
to the cabin
empty-handed that night.
On the drive back, we
picked up a hitchhiker.
A girl, very young, very pretty,
very sociable.
The guys talked her
into staying a while.
I didn't like the idea,
having just gotten
engaged to Alicia,
but I was outnumbered.
Within a few hours,
everyone was pretty drunk.
I could see where
this was heading.
So could the girl.
She wanted to go.
I got out of there, Ben.
I just got in my car
and drove home.
I didn't even bother
to pack my gear.
I knew something terrible
was going to happen.
I was right.
A few days later, the
enclosed article appeared
in the Atlanta Examiner.
It was her.
They arrested some poor black
who lived a couple
of miles away.
He swore he was innocent,
but he was convicted
and sent to prison.
All these years, Ben, I
lived with the knowledge
that one of our friends,
our closest friends,
could very well be a murderer.
Please, please do what I
never had the guts to do.
Find out the truth.
Mr. Matlock!
Now that the court has
your attention, Mr. Matlock,
would you like to
question Mr. Morgan?
Oh, uh, yes.
I, uh, I apologize for my
lack of attention, Your Honor,
and, uh, I'd be happy
to talk to Mr. Morgan.
Conrad.
What do you think about when
you hear the words, "business card"?
What's up?
"Have a problem?"
"Conrad McMasters,
Private Eye." I'm impressed.
Yeah. Pretty good, huh?
Yeah. What's up?
Uh, I want you to
find somebody for me.
Fellow named Calvin Stokes.
He was convicted of
first degree murder in '56.
Spent time at the
Georgia State Pen
and was paroled in '86.
No problem.
Tell him I want to talk to him.
No problem. What about?
Close the door.
Well, look. Speaking of
the devil, look who's here.
Pardon the expression.
It's about time.
We were just talking about
your 28th birthday party, Ben.
Remember that?
You missed it completely.
Oh. Nice one.
Such a great party,
nobody realized
you weren't there until it
was over. At least I didn't.
Oh, this is great.
This is great. We finally
got back together again.
Here.
Okay, well, I'm
afraid, uh, I'm afraid
it's not going to be quite...
the celebration we hoped.
Look at this.
That's, um, a
letter D.B. wrote me
just before he died, all
about that hunting trip
you took without me back in '55.
Including the
part about the girl.
The girl? What girl?
That girl.
D.B. thinks one of us killed
some girl that weekend?
That's crazy.
I spent a lot of time with D.B.
during his final weeks, Ben.
He... he wasn't himself.
I-I had him on morphine...
For pain. He had to
have been hallucinating
when he wrote that.
Why did he keep this
clipping all these years?
Ben, there was no girl;
in the car, in the
cabin, or anywhere else.
You, uh, you haven't
told anybody about this?
I'm up for reelection next year.
My investigator,
but, uh, no names,
and he's closed-mouthed.
Your investigator?
Well...
I have to go through with this.
Uh, I mean, I just have to.
It was, uh, D.B.'s last
request, his dying wish,
so I have to do it.
But, you know, if nothing
comes of it, then well, we'll...
Hey.
That will be that.
Yeah, that will be that.
Well, it's a shame.
You know, if you'd have
been there that weekend
with us, like you should have,
you would know.
You wouldn't have
to go through all this.
Yeah. Yeah.
D.B. was sick.
Yeah.
As I recall, that... that
trip was one of our best.
You mean you actually
brought something home?
Of course we did.
Colds.
From sitting on the
cold, hard ground.
Hey, what do you
say we order, huh?
I'm starved.
What else is new, huh?
Yeah. Hey, Rita?
All right. It's pretty simple.
Mr. Calvin Stokes
still lives in Echo Lake.
It was all I could do
to get him to talk to me.
He absolutely doesn't
want to get involved.
Told me to shove off.
No, actually, he told me
to get the hell out of there.
Maybe he's guilty after all.
I don't know about that,
but he sure wants to
put the past behind him
and get on with his life.
Why did D.B. have
to dump this on me?
Why couldn't he have just
left me a nice tie or something?
Well, daggone it.
The man won't talk to me.
I can't help him. Maybe
the boys are right.
D.B. was real sick
at the end of his life.
I'm done with this case.
All right, well, if
something else comes up,
you got my card.
Yeah, Conrad
McMasters, Private Eye.
See ya, Ben.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
Okay. And, uh,
yeah, we'll be sure...
Ow! Sorry.
Ow!
I'm sorry.
How you doing?
I'm fine.
Did your boys get
a look at my car?
Yeah, what was left of it.
Now if anything occurs to
you, anything at all, call me.
I will.
You be careful, Ben.
Yeah, I-I will. Thanks, pal.
Conrad...
Why don't you go to
the hospital? No, I'm fine.
You don't look fine.
Ow! You look hurt.
How could somebody
blow up my car?
Ignition bomb.
You were lucky.
Bob Brooks was right.
Somebody deliberately
tried to kill me.
You bet.
So, do you have any idea
who might have done it?
No.
Think.
Well, I'm thinking.
You think I'm not
thinking? I'm thinking.
Could you, uh, could you trace
where that bomb came from?
Yeah, I'll find out
where it came from.
And I'm going to
do something else.
I'm going to talk
to your friends.
Oh, no.
Well, then you do it.
No, these are my
oldest, dearest friends.
And you're investigating
them for a murder.
Oh...
If someone from the
past, just from the past,
was trying to kill you, they'd
have done it a long time ago.
Whoever planted that
bomb, has got to be connected
with what's going on
now, and you know that.
I have to get up.
Conrad,
you're wrong.
You've got to be wrong.
Forget it.
I wish I could,
Mr. Stokes, but I can't.
A man I've trusted
for 40 years told me
that you went to
prison for a crime
you most probably didn't commit.
You're damn right I didn't.
Why won't you tell
me what happened?
Now, what's talking
gonna get me?
Now, I did my
time... hard time...
And I just want to forget it.
But if you're innocent...
Keep it down.
Nobody here knows I'm an ex-con.
And I want to keep it that way.
You want to live
your life that way?
Hoping nobody will find out?
Hoping you won't lose your job?
Why won't you let me help you?
Maybe I can clear your name.
Just leave me alone.
No, Mr. Stokes, I can't.
I promised my oldest friend.
Now you're going to take me
and show me what happened,
'cause I'm gonna stay
right here till you do.
Now tell me just
exactly what happened.
Well, I was walking home
from working the night shift
at the mill, like I always did.
I didn't have a car.
I didn't have much
of anything. Yeah.
Anyway, I was in a hurry,
so I took a shortcut
right down this path.
Mm-hmm. Mm.
All right.
Right here, right off the path,
I saw a pair of gloves
kind of caught in the bushes
like somebody tossed them there.
So I went and put them on.
Hell, finders keepers.
It was a cold
morning. Of course.
When I got here, I saw
something a little ways down there.
So I went and looked.
And I saw it was a girl
lying facedown in the brush.
I started pulling her out.
Then I realized her
head was all bloody,
and she was stiff
like she was dead.
Now that scared
the hell out of me.
So I left her there,
and I just ran right
up this hill to the road.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
Yeah.
And you ran back
to the road here.
Then what?
Well, I kept on running.
Pretty soon I heard a
car coming up behind me.
And it was the sheriff.
Well, then I just panicked.
Started running faster.
Then I looked down and
saw the blood from that girl
was all over my new gloves.
So I just took them off and
threw them in the bushes.
Yeah, and then the
sheriff retrieved them.
And after he ran you
down and arrested you,
he turned them
over to the prosecutor
because without them,
they wouldn't have
had much of a case.
Do you really think
you can clear my name?
Well, I'll tell you one thing...
I'm going to give it
my very best shot.
Where on earth did you get this?
Ellen Kingsley let me look
through D.B.'s old photo albums.
Remember what a
camera nut he was.
Yeah. Yeah.
How come you're not in this?
Well, that was the weekend I
couldn't make it, remember?
And that-that's,
that's the weekend
D.B. wrote about in that letter.
Ben, for crying out loud.
Bud... it was the...
It was the only thing
D.B. ever asked me to do.
D.B. was taking morphine
when he wrote that thing.
He was out of his mind.
Excuse me, Bud.
Senator Jacob's
office just called.
Can you make it to lunch with
him and the governor Monday?
Bet I can.
Oh, Senator Jacobs
and the governor...
That's life in the fast lane.
Well, if everything
goes as planned,
in three years, Patty and I will
be moving to Washington DC.
All right!
Oh, wow.
Oh, Bud, I feel
lousy about this,
but I-I just got to
go ahead with it. I...
Ben, there was no girl.
Well, just for a moment,
um, let's suppose
there was a girl.
Let's suppose that you
and Lucas and Jimmy
got her up to that cabin,
and there was a lot
of drinking going on.
This is as hard to think about
as it is to say, but suppose...
something happened
that could have
destroyed your reputations?
Suppose you were
afraid the girl would tell?
We've known each
other for 40 years.
How can you suggest
something like that?
I know, but a bunch of young
men getting drunk like that...
Egging one another on.
The next thing you know...
I don't drink.
Templin's Bar.
There was no alcohol in it.
Maybe not now, but
you sure did then.
No, sir. I had stopped by then.
No, no.
Here. Here.
Do you see that?
The flask coming out of
your pocket right there?
You see that?
You always had that. See that?
Now that I'm
remembering that weekend,
it seemed that everybody
changed after that.
You ran for city council.
Lucas went back
to medical school.
Jimmy joined the church.
Stopped chasing the girls.
That's pure coincidence, Ben.
I hope so, Bud.
I really hope so.
What do you mean
I changed for the better
after that weekend?
Well, that's what Bud said.
Buddy said that?
Well, not in so many words,
but you did join the church
right after that weekend,
didn't you, Jimmy?
Well, sure, but...
And you stopped
chasing the girls.
Now wait a minute.
You make it sound like I
was some kind of Don Juan.
Well, you were.
Always looking at the girls,
and always combing
your hair just right
to be sure they
looked back at you.
That's why you never
wore a hat, remember?
Didn't want to
mess up your hair.
Yeah, well, I was just a kid.
Yeah, look at this here.
Huh? See?
That must have been
taken that weekend.
See your hair?
You must have still
been chasing the girls.
Least that's what Bud thought.
He did, did he? Well, sort of.
And it put me to thinking that
maybe something did happen
between you and
that girl that weekend.
There wasn't any girl
that weekend, Ben.
Beautiful church, Jimmy.
Just beautiful.
I hear that they're
talking about
televising your Sunday services.
Well, I've been approached,
but I don't think
it's going to happen.
I'm just a simple preacher.
Aw, don't be so modest.
You could be the
next Billy Graham.
Ben, excuse me.
Bill, would you put one
of those red hymnals
up on the organist's bench?
Miss Cora gets a little
disturbed if she can't find it.
So I can understand why
D.B.'s letter upset you.
I mean, hell... Oh, I mean heck.
Well, heck, it was bad enough
way back when you
had to watch every step
because your father
was a big bank president,
but I think Bud's right.
You have ten times
more to lose now.
Bud said that, did he?
Something to that effect.
Well, Jimmy, I've taken
up enough of your time.
I know you've got a lot to
do to get ready for services.
So, I'll see ya.
I'll see you on Sunday?
Couldn't hurt.
Yeah.
Bill, would you please finish
up this side of the church?
I have to make a phone call.
It's just that I
have a lot to lose.
I didn't tell him that.
He said you did.
He was bluffing.
He was just trying to get you
to say something about me.
Neither of you told him
about the girl, did you?
I denied she was ever there.
I did, too.
We have nothing to worry about.
Well...
Who's there?
I didn't want to
believe it, I really didn't.
But you did have
a girl in that cabin.
God knows what you did to her.
You're my oldest friends.
35 years ago, you
did something terrible.
Then you conspired
to keep it a secret.
And when it seemed that your
secret would come out in the dark,
one of you... Lucas,
Bud or Jimmy...
One of you tried to kill me.
Ben, I'm sorry,
I'm due in surgery.
Why don't you drop
this whole thing?
I can't... there was a
girl there that weekend.
You all admitted it.
We didn't.
Lucas, I heard you.
You misunderstood.
So you all spent a quiet
weekend alone in that cabin.
That's right. Well, how'd
you come home with colds
from sleeping on the ground?
Oh, we were just joking. No.
Something went on that
weekend, and, by damn,
I'm gonna find
out what. All right,
that's it, I've had it with
your paranoid accusations!
This is harassment,
Ben... I call you my friend,
but that doesn't give you
the right to treat me like this.
Do you mind?
Sylvester!
Sorry about the shirt.
I tell him and I tell him,
but he always ends
up wrecking the shirt.
Hear you're in the
market for some fireworks.
That's what this is about?
Well, we couldn't very
well talk in there, could we?
What are you looking for?
Actually, I'm looking for you.
See, somebody tried to kill my
friend with an emission bomb,
and I think they
bought it from you.
I have no idea...
Who'd you sell bombs to...
I'll be seeing you around.
What?! Are you crazy?!
See, I made a phone call,
and if you touch
me one more time,
there's gonna be more cops
here than you ever seen in your life.
Now, you tell me who it was,
and maybe we can
end this like friends.
It was a phone order, my man.
You don't know who
you sold the bomb to?
That's right.
Who paid you?
Look, I leave the
merchandise on the curb.
Car pulls up, guy
opens the door,
takes the merchandise,
leaves the cash, drives off.
No name, no face.
What'd the car look like?
Brown.
Come on.
Mercedes.
560SEL.
License number.
You wrote it down...
The guy could've been
leaving you a sack
of newspapers.
Thank you, Sylvester.
Georgia plate:
U-P-L-7-9-0.
How you doing? Hi.
I'm Conrad McMasters.
I'm working for Ben Matlock.
I don't have time for this.
Let me just ask
you... one question,
just one question. No.
How could you do it?
What, you've known
the man for 40 years.
You're supposed to be
one of Ben's best friends.
How could you try to kill him?
I did not such thing.
Don't give me that!
You bought the bomb.
That's impossible!
They identified your
car... There's a witness.
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna call the police
forensics department,
they're gonna come down here,
they're gonna go
through this car
with a fine-tooth comb.
I didn't buy any bombs.
Wait a minute.
A lot of people
could've done it.
I keep my car locked,
but anybody who knows me...
knows I keep a spare
set of keys right there.
Does Ben?
Ben, what you're saying is
that I stole Lucas Sinclair's car,
then used it to pick up a bomb,
which I then
planted in your car.
If I remembered where
that key box was hidden,
you might have, too.
I don't believe this, Ben.
How long have we been friends?
You couldn't pick up that bomb
with your own car,
could you? Ben,
what in the hell
has gotten into you?
Lucas told me
everything that happened
in that cabin that weekend.
Lucas told you? Told you what?
Everything. Nothing happened.
You're fishing, Ben.
Lucas didn't tell you anything.
He told me about the card game.
All right.
So you talked to Lucas,
and he gave you his
version of that weekend.
But I'm not gonna get hung
for something I didn't do.
You've lied ever since
you read D.B.'s letter.
What, am I supposed
to believe you now?
Then I'll have
to prove it to you.
Lucas tell you we
decided to draw cards?
Yeah.
Person who got the ace spades
would take care of the girl?
Did he tell you who
dealt the cards that night?
You did.
Pulled the ace, the
king and the queen,
shuffled 'em,
and dealt 'em.
Your turn.
Ace of spades.
Do it again.
It's the ace of spades.
I know.
I've got the queen.
There's the king.
You marked the cards.
Just like I did 35
years ago, Ben.
I didn't want to be the one
to get the ace of spades,
so I made damn sure I didn't.
This is a hearing on
defendant's extraordinary writ
in the case of The People
of the State of Georgia
v. Calvin Stokes,
case number 7-6-1-5-3-9.
Appearance as counsel?
Brit Hudson, Deputy
District Attorney
on behalf of Fulton
County, Your Honor.
Benjamin Matlock for the
defendant, Calvin Stokes.
Mr. Stokes is present.
Your petition
presents a very unusual
situation, Mr. Matlock.
You understand that I must
make every presumption
in favor of the trial court's
conviction of your client?
Understood, Your Honor,
but I think a horrible
injustice has occurred.
The evidence we'll hear will
demonstrate that to this court.
Very well... you may
call your first witness.
I was with Buddy Carlson,
Lucas Sinclair and D.B. Kingsley.
As you well know, we
used to go hunting together
up at Echo Lake.
Yeah, j-just...
just good, clean fun.
Well, we thought so then.
We were young men,
little more than boys.
Like a lot of young
men, we were...
a little wild and reckless.
Sort of, uh, sowing wild oats.
You know what it was like.
We used to go hunting,
we'd play cards a
little, drink a little,
but... we never did anything
we were really ashamed of.
Until...
that weekend.
Pastor Hubert...
Jimmy...
you have a choice.
You know that.
You can lie and
hope your reputation
as a preacher and a good man
will cause this
court to believe you,
or you can...
practice what you preach,
tell the truth,
cleanse your conscience,
correct a wrong
that you've held
secret for 35 years.
Can you make that choice?
I've thought of nothing
else for days, Ben.
I haven't eaten, I
haven't slept, but I...
I have prayed.
Will you tell this court
what happened that weekend
in November 1955?
Everything D.B. said
in that letter is true.
There was a girl.
And after D.B. left,
things got a little wild.
She... threatened to tell on us,
said she was going
straight to the police,
that she was gonna...
see us all in jail, so we...
at first, laughed... We
didn't think she meant it.
But...
then she ran out of the cabin.
We went after her.
We... we realized that
she could ruin our lives
before they even begun,
so we...
caught her,
locked her in the
shed behind the cabin
while we...
decided what to do.
Which was what?
Ben, we were so young
and drunk and scared.
No, no, no, there's no
excuse; what I did was wrong.
What we did was a
sin against that poor girl,
and I... I cannot allow
myself to make excuses.
We decided that...
she would carry
out her threat, that...
we'd go to jail, and we...
our lives would be ruined.
We decided we...
couldn't let her go.
So... we decided one of us
was gonna have to kill her.
One of you?
Mm-hmm.
And how did you decide
which one?
I'm ashamed to
say this, I really am.
We played cards.
We took the queen, the king,
the ace of spades from the deck.
Buddy Carlson
shuffled and dealt them.
We agreed that
whoever got the ace...
I can't say it.
Whoever got the ace of spades
would murder that
poor, unfortunate girl.
Is that what you can't say?
You must say it out loud,
so the court can hear, Jimmy.
You must.
Whoever got the ace...
would murder the girl.
Um, then what
happened, Pastor Hubert?
We, uh...
slept in the woods that
night, so that none of us
except the murderer
would know who killed her.
I didn't even look at my card
until I got to the place
where I was gonna sleep.
It was the ace.
So I went to the
shed and unlocked it.
The girl was sitting in
there inside, terrified.
Almost as terrified as I was.
I stood there, frozen.
And I let her go.
What did you say?
She ran past me out the door,
and I didn't stop
her, I let her go.
I couldn't kill her.
Ben, I couldn't kill her.
I was a sinner, but
I was no murderer.
Oh, come on, Jimmy, you
expect us to believe that?
It's the truth... I let her go.
And I never saw her again.
Till I saw the paper
several days later,
and read that somebody else
had murdered her.
You mean...
all these years, and
you've never told the others
it wasn't you
who killed the girl?
There was no
reason to tell them.
They wouldn't have
believed me, anyway.
They'd have thought
I just... covered it up.
I h... I have...
no further questions
for this witness.
Witness may step down.
They had the real
murderer all along.
Should've quit while
you were ahead.
Three friendships,
three lives destroyed.
For nothing.
Your Honor.
The witness is excused.
You wrecked my life!
Now not only does
everybody know I'm an ex-con,
but they think
I'm guilty as hell!
Well, well, maybe
it's not over yet.
It is for me!
Now I have to find a new
place, a new job and a new home
and start all over again!
Well, yeah, but
if... No! No more!
You know, you know
what I really kick myself for?
For being a sucker!
No, you made me
hope for something
that I had no
business hoping for!
So from now on, leave me alone!
Well...
Well, we got to do something.
What is that?
Everything I could get
from the original trial.
Newspaper clippings and
pictures of the, of the evidence
and pictures of the victim.
And-and here are,
here are, uh, pictures
that D.B. took that day.
You lay them out over
there, and I'll lay all these out.
And we'll pray heaven
we'll see something.
Do you see a good
picture of those gloves
that he...
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, that's
good, that's... yeah.
Yeah.
Now see if you can find
picture was dated
that Sunday morning.
Yeah, there.
That's it, that's it.
Okay.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
What?
What? Let's go.
What do you got?
Well, something good I hope.
We need to see...
the weatherman.
So then you drew
cards to determine
which one of you would kill her.
Yes, I'm sorry to say we did.
B-Before you drew them,
unbeknownst to the others,
to make sure you did
not get the ace of spades,
you marked it.
Is that correct?
I didn't want to kill her.
Well, you were the
nephew of the mayor
from a... highly
respected, influential family
with a reputation
to be protected,
not to mention your
own political aspirations.
I did not want
to kill that girl.
I think you did.
What you didn't want was
for the others to know about it.
Objection.
That's not a question,
it's a statement.
Sustained.
I remind you, Mr. Matlock,
that this is not a trial.
Uh, since you knew
which card was the ace,
you knew that Jimmy
Hubert had drawn it,
didn't you?
Yes. And you followed him
to the shed that
night, didn't you?
No.
And when you saw that he was
unable to go through with
it and let the girl run away,
you went after her, didn't you?
No, I did not.
And you caught her
somewhere in the brush,
and you hit her,
and she was dead, and
you left her there, didn't you?
- No, I did not.
- Your Honor,
where is defense
counsel going with all this?
That is the court's question
as well, Mr. Matlock.
You're not meeting
your burden of proof
by these off-the-wall inquiries.
Do you have something
more concrete?
Yes, I do, Your
Honor. Then get to it,
would you please?
Yes, Your Honor.
I believe you all have a
copy of these pictures.
Uh, the gloves
that you were
wearing that weekend,
what'd they look like?
That was 35 years ago.
Who remembers?
Well, let me ask you this, then.
This is a picture of, uh,
Jimmy Hubert, Lucas
Sinclair and you,
with your gloves on.
Now, th-this picture was
made that weekend, wasn't it?
Yes. D.B. took it
and sent copies
to all three of us.
Right,
right, right.
You know, when you
compare your gloves...
There's a blowup of
one of your gloves...
With the gloves that,
uh, Calvin Stokes had
when the sheriff arrested
him at the scene of the crime,
you find something
very interesting.
They're the same gloves.
They're the same brand, maybe.
No.
The same gloves.
The glove in this picture
is the same as the
glove in this picture.
You see that little tear
right along the seam?
Identical.
Then I must have lost it,
and he must have found them.
Oh, you lost them.
Hell, I don't remember;
it's 35 years ago.
I mean, how else would he have
wound up with them?
I tell you how.
'Cause you were
wearing those gloves
when you killed that
girl, got her blood on them
and threw them away.
The next morning, Calvin
Stokes comes along,
he picks them up, and that's
how he wound up with them.
No.
If he found them, it's because
I dropped them in the woods
someplace earlier that day.
No.
You were wearing those gloves
when you left that
shed to kill that girl,
and I can prove it.
How in the hell
do you know that?
D.B., D.B. took pictures
of every hunt, all
the way through.
He had a camera always
present, remember?
From beginning to end.
Here at the beginning,
here at the end.
Even D.B. got in this
picture using a trip wire.
See the bulb?
See there?
You're wearing your gloves.
You know,
I'm not sure which trip that
picture was taken on, Ben.
It, uh, maybe was
taken on a different trip.
Eh, come on, Bud.
Come on, now.
You know how organized D.B. was.
Here's the original to this one.
He wrote the date on
the back of every picture.
See? 11/55.
November '55.
It's his handwriting, too.
Yes, but, uh, how do you know
it wasn't taken in the morning
when we were starting out?
Because...
what are you
holding in your hand?
It's a flask?
What was in the flask?
Probably bourbon.
You know, there was
one hard and fast rule
we had about
alcohol and hunting.
I remember.
No drinking till
the end of the day
when we were all done. Why?
Well, because alcohol
and loaded guns don't mix.
Right.
And you were drinking.
See?
Cap is off the flask.
Since you were drinking,
it must have been the
end of the day, right?
I don't remember.
Well, you got your gloves on.
And you got your gloves on here.
And the date on that
picture is the same.
11/55.
All the fellas are wearing
the same stuff they're wearing
in all the other pictures.
Must have been cold
in that cabin that night.
You got your gloves on.
Well, that's because the picture
was taken the night before.
It was on Friday
when we first arrived.
No.
The picture was
taken on Saturday
after you locked that
poor girl in the shed
and before Jimmy
Hubert went up to kill her.
How in the hell
do you know that?
Because D.B. is
not in the picture.
Well, he was the
one taking it! No!
You were taking
it with the trip wire.
See the bulb in your hand?
See the glove
there with the bulb?
D.B. had long gone.
You probably wanted him
to think that nothing unusual
had happened since he had left.
That's why you took it.
The same thing with this
picture Sunday morning.
Make D.B. think like you
were happy as anything.
See there?
Now, look.
Gloves... gloves...
gloves...
no gloves.
What happened to them?
That picture was taken
Saturday not Sunday,
and I-I just hadn't gotten
around to putting them on yet.
No, it was Sunday.
And again, D.B.
didn't take that picture.
You did.
With the trip wire.
See the bulb in your hand?
And you know something else?
I called the weather
bureau, and that weekend,
that Saturday,
was cool and overcast all day.
But Sunday morning
was bright, sunshiny,
not a cloud in the sky.
You see?
And it was cold that morning.
Sunday morning was
much colder than it was
all day Saturday.
And that... yet there you stand
bare-handed.
Why, Bud?
Why?
I think I know.
You had tossed
your gloves away...
after you murdered
that young
hitchhiker, hadn't you?
Ben, I...
It's hard...
to keep coming up with answers
to these very difficult
questions, isn't it, Bud?
Maybe... maybe you'd better
talk to your lawyer before
you answer that last one.
Yes.
Good luck, Mr. Stokes.
Thank you,
Mr. Matlock.
Conrad.
Take care.
Mr. Matlock.
Well... Yeah.
You know...
you think you know
people, and you don't.
I thought I knew
all those fellas.
All the 25 years
Mr. Stokes was in prison,
I thought I knew them
and that we were friends.
And we weren't.
Funny, huh?
In a way, I guess.
Well,
all you can do is
the best you can.
That's what Mama always told me.
Yeah? Best you can?
You bet.
Hey.
Let's go down to Ray Templin's
and hear a little music.
What say?
Yeah.
www.tvsubtitles.net